{
    "id": "5166c2c917ee45418466bdcdb0da55ea",
    "title": "Gerunds or Infinitives | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "a7caca96ed1149e1b9c66e8aca13d666",
            "title": "Gerunds or Infinitives | Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He insisted ……………… paid at once.",
                    "description": "After a verb + preposition, we normally use the –ing form of the following verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "on being",
                        "on to be",
                        "to be"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t like the idea ………………….. old.",
                    "description": "After a noun + preposition, we usually use the –ing form of the following verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to get",
                        "of getting",
                        "to get"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am not very good …………………..",
                    "description": "After an adjective + preposition, we usually use the –ing form of the following verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to dance",
                        "at dancing",
                        "in dancing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I was interested .....................… that my ancestors were from Burma.",
                    "description": "We use an infinitive after learn to talk about successfully learning something. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "in learning",
                        "to learn",
                        "to learning"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t think they mean ………………….. for the moment.",
                    "description": "When ‘mean’ means ‘intend’, it is followed by an infinitive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "getting married",
                        "to get married",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you want to pass the test that will mean …………………. hard.",
                    "description": "When ‘mean’ means ‘involve’, it is followed by an –ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to work",
                        "working",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I’m beginning ………………… things better.",
                    "description": "Infinitives are preferred after continuous forms of begin and start.",
                    "answers": [
                        "understanding",
                        "to understand",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am not accustomed …………………. alone.",
                    "description": "After ‘be accustomed to’, we can use an infinitive or an –ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to live",
                        "to living",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are still waiting for them ……………..",
                    "description": "Some verbs are followed by for + object + infinitive. Wait is one of them. An –ing form is not usually possible in these cases. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "arriving",
                        "to arrive",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They are talking about ………………… to the country.",
                    "description": "We use an –ing form after a preposition.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to move",
                        "moving",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They repaired the roof instead ………………… on holiday.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "to go",
                        "of going",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I regret ……………….. my job. It was a big mistake.",
                    "description": "We use an -ing form after regret to refer to the past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to quit",
                        "quitting",
                        "to quitting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}